CORMAC MCGLOIN

PRODUCT DESIGNER

Skills/Methodologies

User-centred design

User research

User interface design

Wireframes

Interaction design

User journeys

Coded prototypes

Agile

Scrum

Kanban

Tools

Figma

Sketch

Miro

Framer

Principle

Zeplin

Photoshop

Illustrator

InDesign

After Effects

Programming

HTML 5

CSS 3

SASS/SCSS

Javascript

React

GSAP

Git

Education

Bachelor of Arts, Photography

University of East London

2008 - 2011

National Diploma, Graphic Design

Wigan and Leigh College

2004 - 2006

About me

I am a product designer who helps businesses to understand their customers and improve their products. Combining an eye for visual design with a methodical approach to research and frontend development skills has allowed me to take projects from the planning stages right through to implementation and beyond.

Experience

Senior product designer

Credit Karma | February 2021 - present

I work closely with the product, analytics and customer service teams to gain insights into real user problems. Based on these problems, I design improved member journeys in the credit cards and personal loans marketplace.

Senior product design consultant (contract)

Moneyfarm | August 2020 - January 2021

I helped to deliver optimised website and app experiences by improving the consistency and efficiency of the design system. The work I did helped standardise the design and engineering teams ways of working and made the design and handover process more effective.

Senior design consultant (contract)

Zoopla | June 2019 - March 2020

I was instrumental in the planning, designing and implementation of a centralised design system at Zoopla. This led to increased consistency for the end users, greater efficiency for the designers and engineers and an improved onboarding experience for new team members.

Senior UI/UX designer (contract)

Arroe | May 2017 - Present

I led the design of the website and app for Arroe's smart battery solution. I also designed the packaging for their product and the collateral for the business.

Senior UI/UX designer (contract)

River Island | July 2018 - March 2019

I improved the user experience throughout the River Island site. Research methodologies included: competitor analysis, white paper research, data analysis, in-person interviews, usability testing and multivariate testing.

Senior UI designer (contract)

Havas Life Medicom | June 2018

I produced user interface designs for a pharmaceutical website.

Email designer & developer (contract)

Harrods | April - May 2018

I designed and developed various email campaigns for Harrods and their brand partners.

Senior UI designer (contract)

Beauty Pie | January - March 2018

I audited current UI patterns and helped create a unified design language to make the user journey more intuitive and consistent. I hosted daily calls with developers to aid with code implementation.

Senior UI designer (contract)

Spafax | November - December 2017

I produced user interface designs and style guides for the websites of various airlines.

Lead designer & lead front-end developer (contract)

Catapult Sports | July - October 2017

Lead designer and front-end developer for the new PlayerTek website.

Senior UI designer (contract)

Topshop | February - June 2017

I helped to unify the desktop and mobile user experiences by creating consistent UI patterns across all device sizes and producing a style guide that would be the single source of truth.

Senior UX/UI designer (contract)

Hudson Shoes | July 2016 - February 2017

I redesigned key pages of the website including the homepage, PLP, PDP and checkout journey. Designed and coded key landing pages and email campaigns.

Digital & print designer (contract)

Lufthansa | September - December 2016

I produced digital and print designs for Lufthansa and its subsidiaries.

Senior UI designer (contract)

Practicology | May - July 2016

I designed key pages for the Hobbycraft and Dreams websites.